brain.fm 2018-11-21

# Brain.fm: Music to improve focus, meditation & sleep.

Brain.FM, Inc. (“Brain.FM”) takes the privacy and security of our customers seriously. Brain.FM provides this Internet Privacy Policy because our users have a right to know what information we collect, how it is used, and how it is protected. This Privacy Policy and theTerms of Useon our site outline the terms and conditions under which you use our website and products. Use, collection, and disclosure of your information will be governed by the terms of this Privacy Policy. This policy may be amended from time to time and was last updated on May 23rd, 2018.

## Registration for Brain.FM Users

In order receive emails sent by Brain.FM you must first complete a signup form by registering online through our web site or through the app on your mobile device. During registration, you are required to give contact information (such as first and last name and email address). Brain.FM collects personally identifiable information from our users during the initial signup process as well as during surveys or preference requests. We use this information to contact you with product updates, newsletters, and special promotions which you have expressed interest in receiving. You may opt out of these emails at any time.

Additional communications may include offers, newsletters, product or company updates, special promotions, surveys, and unsubscribe confirmations.

Personal data processed by Brain.FM shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for the intended processing or legal purposes. Users have the right to request that their information be deleted, and once the request has been verified the data will be deleted within 30 days.

## Information We Collect

As part of our normal business practice we collect and use personal information you voluntarily provide to us. Personal information such as your name, email address, and other pertinent contact information is collected for the following purposes:

  * Product Related Data:
    * Product Use, Product Experience, and Product Improvement
  * Business Related Data:
    * Customer Support and Troubleshooting
    * Operations and Transactions
    * Communication and Marketing.

## Uses of Customer Information

Your name and email addresses is used only to send email that was requested. Brain.FM follows an opt-in permission-based email enrollment policy. Brain.FM will not send unsolicited, bulk or commercial offers, or advertisements. All emails contain links on how to unsubscribe from the client list. You may leave our lists at any time for any reason. If you have any questions or feel that you received unsolicited email or an unsolicited SMS message please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Brain.FM will use personally identifiable information to contact you when responding to email support requests and other direct requests for information from Brain.FM. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

## Surveys or Contests

From time to time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in web-based contests or surveys. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name address and phone number(s)), demographic information (such as zip code) and personal preference information (such as your opinions). We use this information to better understand who uses our products and how we can make them better.

Brain.FM may use a third-party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company is prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with any other third party unless we give you prior notice and you elect to permit the provision of that information to the third party. 

Brain.FM retains ownership of your data, as the data controller, and any information processing involving your data will be done by processors held to the same data privacy compliance standards as us. We agree that we will not rent, sell or otherwise provide your information to outside parties whom do not meet the appropriate compliance standards. 

In the event of a sale, merger, consolidation, liquidation, reorganization, or acquisition we may transfer your information. In that instance, any acquirer will be subject to our same obligations under this Privacy Policy, including your rights to access and choice. We will notify you of the change either by sending you an email or posting a notice on our website.

## Service Providers

When you sign up to receive emails, we will share your enrollment information with our marketing, mailing, and analytics providers so that our third party vendors can provide marketing and strategic business insight services to us. From time to time, Brain.FM may use a third-party vendor to fulfill promotions on our behalf as well. Any third parties or third party vendors are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose other than the purpose outlined in their contract. All third party vendors are expected to maintain the same level of compliance or better that we maintain at Brain.FM.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to (a) protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our company; (b) protect and defend Brain.FM’s rights or property or the users our services, and (c) act under demanding circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of our services or the public.

## Opt-out/Unsubscribe

f you no longer wish to receive our communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication or by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), please include your email address in the body of the message as well as writing the word, “unsubscribe” in the subject line.

## Clear Gifs

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “Opt-out/Unsubscribe”.

## Cookies

Brain.FM places a “cookie” on the browser of a Brain.FM.com user’s computer to store and sometimes track information about you. Cookies are information files that your web browser places on the hard drive of your computer when you visit a website. Cookies were designed to help a web site recognize the prior visits to a site made by a user’s browser. Cookies cannot damage user files, pass on computer viruses, capture email addresses or read information from a user’s hard drive.

cookie can be used to measure certain traffic patterns on Brain.FM’s website. For example, when you sign in to our website using your email and password, we store your unique information, and the time you signed in, in a cookie on your hard disk. This cookie allows you to move from page to page at the site without having to sign in again on each page. Brain.FM may also use cookies to track your progress while using Brain.FM’s Services. At Brain.FM, we do not generally store personal information into cookies, but we may combine a randomly generated identifier collected through cookies with other Personal Information that we have about you, to tell us, for example, whether you have an account with us.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. You will also have the opportunity to accept or decline cookies in a browser pop-up. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use some features of Brain.FM’s website and services that depend on cookies.

## Links to Other Sites

Emails that we send may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Brain.FM, such as social media or other outside parties. Please be aware that Brain.FM is not responsible for the privacy practices of those other sites and do not exercise authority over such web sites. Brain.FM therefore assumes no responsibility for the privacy and data collection policies and procedures of such linked web sites, nor for the content or reliability of such web sites. If you choose to access a third party web site, you do so at your own risk.

You have the right to access the personal information that we hold about you. This may be called a ‘Subject Access Request’. If you make a request for your information we will provide it to you or your designated agent free of charge within a reasonable timeframe.

Before providing personal information to you or your designated agent on your behalf, we may ask for proof of identity and sufficient information about your interactions with us that we can locate your personal information.

If any of the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or out of date, you may ask us to correct it or correct, update, delete, or deactivate it yourself by making the change on our member information page or by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

You have the right to object to us processing your personal information if we are not entitled to use it any more, to have your information deleted if we are keeping it too long, or have its processing restricted in certain circumstances. 

If you would like to exercise any of these rights or lodge a complaint, please contact us using the information as set out below.

## Data Security

We will retain a copy of your information in accordance with law and for only so long as necessary to provide you with high quality and consistent services including marketing services and account information.

Brain.FM has put in place certain technological and procedural security functions in order to protect the personal information it collects, uses or transfers from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. Brain.FM uses firewalls to help prevent outside parties from accessing our database server through the Internet, and physical access to the database server is restricted to authorized individuals.

When transferring personally identifiable information to and from third parties Brain.FM uses SSL & SFTP (Secure FTP) (which includes SHA-2 encryption), as required for Email Sender and Provider Coalition (ESPC) membership. 

Information collected by our website or transferred to us from other sources will be processed in the United States, Singapore, and the European Union.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will publicize such changes by means of a notice on our home page by providing thirty (30) days’ notice to you by displaying a prominent notice, in all caps, above the text of the Privacy Statement.

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us:

  * Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
  * Mail: Transparent Inc. dba Brain.fm 4425 N Knox Ave, Suite 190 (Inside Fort Knox Studios), Chicago, IL 60641, United States;
